Abdulraheem Quwam

Data Scientist

<u>Devquams@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdulraheem-quwamwww.github.com/dev-abdulraheem</u>

Summary

An accomplished Data Analyst with extensive experience in predictive modeling and data processing algorithms, as well as scripting language including python. Capable of Providing actionable business intelligence to support strategic initiatives and implement the solutions derived to improve return on investment.

Experience

INN KEEPER, Hybrid - Data Analysis Facilitator

JAN 2023 - PRESENT

 Guiding, encouraging and motivating learners through their data analytics journey, and also responsible for the marking and provision of feedback on learner projects and assessments.

QUELIB, Remote - Python Developer

SEP 2022 - DEC 2022

 Implemented the python programming language and several python packages to create the QueLib library to ease data cleaning and preprocessing steps.

Neo Docto Inc, Remote - Data Analyst Associate

JUN 2022 - SEPT 2022

- Utilized analytical and technical expertise to provide insights and proposals to support business improvement.
- Conducted Business analysis to understand business needs and requirements to translate into conceptual designs.
- Worked with the business clients to identify business issues, data collection, data mining, analyzing data, evaluating and presenting data solutions.

FREELANCE, Remote - Data Scientist

DEC 2021 - PRESENT

- Working with clients from multiple industries in data collection, building dashboards, and presenting them on a contract basis in order to provide actionable business intelligence to support strategic initiatives.
- Implementing Predictive models using various machine learning tools / Algorithms to predict future possibilities.

Education

Talent Model College, Lagos - SSCE. Economics.

MAY 2013 - JULY 2019

Skills

- Python Programming Language
- Relational Database (MySQL)
- Microsoft Power BI, Microsoft Excel
- Machine Learning (Supervised, Unsupervised)
- Data Analysis, Effective Communication, Critical Thinking, Problem-Solving

Selected Projects

Yusen Logistics

Pepsi Data Science Challenge

Movember Fundraiser

Employee's Churn Prediction

Awards

Top performer, Data Science Nigeria Hackathon. Data Science Nigeria (DSN) is a frontline Artificial Intelligence (AI) non-profit committed to driving the solution-oriented application of Artificial Intelligence in Nigeria, with a focus on building world-class AI knowledge, research, and innovation ecosystem that delivers transformational research, business use applications, AI-first start-ups, employability, and good social use cases.